So the first step is to figure out a way for
第一步是找到一种方法来让
the Word Adapter to tell if the word object has an image or not.
WordAdapter 判断 Word 对象是否具有图片
So let's take a look at the Word Adapter file and Android studio.
我们在 Android studio 中看看 WordAdapter 文件
Now here the Word Adapter class, remember that we only want to
在这个 WordAdapter 类中 只有当单词具有图片时
execute these lines of code that set up the ImageView, if there is an image for
我们才希望执行这几行代码
the word.
即设置 ImageView
In order to do this, we should create and expose another method in the Word
为此 我们应该在 Word 类中创建并研究下另一个方法
class, which should tell us if the word at the current position has an image.
该方法会告诉我们当前位置的单词是否具有图片
So I want to hop over to work class and define that method.
转到 Word 类并定义该方法
So at the bottom of the word class, I'm going to create a public method called
在 Word 类的底部 我将创建一个公共方法
hasImage and have it return a boolean value.
叫做 hasImage 并使其返回布尔值
So I want this method to turn true, if the word has an image and
如果单词具有图片 该方法会返回 true
false, if there is no image, and remember it's important to always add
如果没有图片 则返回 false 记住一定要写上注释
some comments to help readers understand your code I'm going to add that here.
帮助他人理解你的代码 我在这里写上注释
Now how should we determine if a word has an image?
那么我们该如何判断某个单词是否有图片呢？
Well let's scroll up to the top of the word class.
我们滚动到 Word 类的顶部
And remember that we had this variable here,
注意这里有个变量
mImageResourceId and we can check that.
即 mImageResourceId 我们可以研究下该方法
We'll note that it doesn't actually help us predict what image is referenced.
发现它实际上并不能帮助我们预测引用的是什么图片
However in our case, we only need to use it to check whether or
但是在这里 我们只需利用它来判断单词是否具有
not there is a valid image.
有效的图片即可
All right so this is actually a really good use case for constant values.
这里常量就派上用场了
We can create a constant that represents the no image state, and
我们可以创建一个常量 表示无图片状态
I'm going to do that here.
我将在这里创建
So I created a variable called NO_IMAGE_PROVIDED, it's in all caps
我创建了一个变量 叫做 NO_IMAGE_PROVIDED 全为大写
because it's a constant, and each word is separated by an underscore.
因为它是常量 并且每个单词用下划线分隔
Now I'm going to set this to a constant value of negative one, and
我将其设置为常量值 -1
I use negative one,
使用 -1 是因为
because it's out of the range of all the possible valid resource ID.
它超出了有效资源 ID 的所有可能范围
Also notice that this constant is a private variable,
同时注意 这个常量是私有变量
because we only need to use it within the word class.
因为我们只需要在 Word 类里用到它
So with this constant created,
创建完该常量后
I'm going to set the image variable to start at the no image state by default.
我将这个图片变量设置为默认情况下以无图片状态开始
So I'm going to set that equal to our no image constant here.
所以设为等于这个无图片常量
Now as soon as this variable's updated to something else,
一旦这个变量更新为其他内容
we know that the Word has an image.
我们就知道该单词具有图片
So this means that if there is an image in this contractor,
意味着如果该构造函数里有图片
this variable will be updated to something else, and
这个变量将更新为其他内容
you would know that the word has an image and otherwise if no image is from
你就会知道该单词具有图片 如果没有提供图片的话
right in, then the image resource ID will say the same.
那么图片资源 ID 将保持不变
So, remain with the constant value negative one.
也就是保持常量值 -1
So, let's go back down to the has image method, which we still need to complete.
现在回到 hasImage 方法 我们依然需要写完整了
So, in this method we just need to check whether the image variable is equal or
在这个方法中 我们需要检查图片变量是否等于
not equal to the no image provided constant, and that will like this and
NO_IMAGE_PROVIDED 常量 应该是这样的
by the way the exclamation mark followed by the equal sign means not equal to.
顺便提下 “!=”表示不等于
So the result of this expression will be either true or false, and
该表达式的结果要么是 true 要么是 false
that value gets returned as the return value of this method.
该值会返回为该方法的返回值
So no logic can be a little bit confusing, but I like you to try and
我知道这里的逻辑有点难懂 但是还是请大家尽量
follow along.
跟上课程节奏
So if the image resource variable is not equal to negative one,
如果图片资源变量不等于 -1
then there is a valid image, and the method should return true, however if
那么就存在有效的图片 该方法应返回 true
the image variable Is equal to negative one then there is no image for
但是如果该图片变量等于 -1 那么该单词就没有图片
this word and the method to return false.
该方法会返回 false
Now we don't want to force the word adopter class to do the quality check,
我们不希望强迫 WordAdopter 类对图片本身作出检查
because all it cares about is whether or not there is an image.
因为它只关心是否存在图片
So the word adapter doesn't need to know all the nitty gritty details of how we
所以 WordAdopter 不需要知道我们如何使用 Word 类中的
used to cost in our world class decide this.
常量来判断是否存在图片的细节信息
And hence this is why all the logic is within the work class.
因此所有的逻辑内容都位于 Word 类中
All right. So good job so far.
恩 很棒
Now in the word class we have exposed a public method called hasImage.
在 Word 类中 我们使用了一个公共方法 叫做 hasImage
So let's switch back over to the word adapter class and
我们切换到 WordAdapter 类
see how we can use this hasImage method on the word object.
看看如何在 Word 对象上使用该 hasImage 方法
So now this line of code they were concerned with.
对于这行我们关心的代码
Remember that we can use conditional logic, such as an if else statement.
我们可以使用条件逻辑 例如 if else 语句
So that our code behaves differently depending on whether or
这样我们的代码会根据单词是否具有图片
not the word has an image.
而产生不同的行为
So this if statement checks that if the current word has an image,
这个 if 语句检查发现当前单词具有图片的话
then we can proceed as we did before and set the correct image
则和之前的操作一样 将 Word 对象上的正确图片
from the word object on to the image view, and otherwise if that's not true,
设置到 ImageView 上 如果不为真的话
we should hide the image view and that will go in our else statement.
则隐藏 ImageView 并转到 else 语句
So earlier, I showed you some code on how to change the visibility of a view
之前我展示了一些代码 告诉大家如何更改
when the app is running.
视图在应用运行时的可见性
So remember using the set visibility method,
通过 setVisibility 方法
we can completely hide the image, so to do so I'm going to set it to gone.
我们可以完全隐藏图片 为此 我将其设为 GONE
So either through experimentation or reading the documentation on your own.
希望你通过实验研究或阅读文档
I hope you found out that gone means that the view is hidden and
已经发现 GONE 表示视图被隐藏了
doesn't take up any space in the layout.
并且不占用布局的任何空间
Now compare this with the invisible state which means that the view is
现在请将这个状态与 INVISIBLE 状态对比下 后者是指视图被隐藏
hidden but still takes up space in the layout.
但是仍然占用了布局中的空间
In our up if we set the image view to be invisible there would be a blank space
在我们的应用中 如果我们将 ImageView 设为 INVISIBLE
left on the left hand side of the list item and we don't want that.
那么列表项左侧依然会出现一个空白区域 我们不希望出现这种情况
So instead we've set the image view to gone, so that hides it completely.
所以我们将 ImageView 设为 GONE 将其完全隐藏起来
Here I'm want to add some comments describing what this line of code does.
我将在这里添加一些注释 解释这行代码的作用
Now back in the if statement.
现在回到 if 语句
We need to be extra explicit code and set the visibility to be visible.
我们的代码需要非常明确 当我们的确具有图片的时候
If we do have an image before we do this because views get reused.
我们需要将 Visibility 设为 VISIBLE 这么操作是为了重复利用视图
So if the view was previously hidden, we want to make sure that it's made visible
如果视图之前被隐藏了 我们则希望在 ImageView 上设置新的图片时
again when we set a new image on the image view.
该视图再次变得可见
All right there were a lot of changes but
哇 更改了好多代码啊
let's test our device down see what happen.
我们在设备上测试下 看看效果如何
All right so first testing and phrases.
首先测试下 Phrases
All right that looks good, no images.
看起来正常 没有图片
Now let's try numbers.
再来试试 Numbers
Nice.
不错
Images.
有图片
Family members.
Family Members
Cool, got those cute faces there.
好酷 这些人脸可爱啊
And then colors.
然后是 Colors
That's got the nice spectrum.
具有各种光谱
So, perfect, so all our categories are functioning as we hoped.
很不错 所有类别都能按照预期的正常运行
So going back to the quiz.
回到测试题
Let's answer these two questions.
回答下这两个问题
So for the phrase list item,
对于 Phrase 列表项
the image view needs to be gone, because we want to hide it.
ImageView 需要设为 GONE 因为我们想要隐藏它
And we don't want to take up any space in the layout.
并且不想占用布局中的任何空间
That way the two text views can shift all the way to the left.
这样两个 TextView 可以移到最左侧
Now for all the other list items.
对于所有其他列表项
The image view needs to be set to visible.
ImageView 需要设为 VISIBLE
So that the user can see it.
这样用户才能看见该视图
So this reflects what we did in our code.
这些反映了我们在代码中执行的操作
And our app looks the way we want it to.
应用外观也达到预期效果
So really great job on this very challenging quiz.
恭喜大家完成了这道非常难的测试题